# **Muhammad Sohail Shams**

Add: Høje Gladsaxe 67, 2 TH Søborg, 2860 Copenhagen.

PH: +45 50909122

E-Mail: sohailshamsramay@gmail.com



I have a diverse educational background and over 6 years of experience within the field of marketing, management and administration. I am well organized and structured person who have a broad knowledge of working within sales, marketing and customer service. I am always keen in learning new technologies.

## **IT Skills:**

### Github Repositories & Project Portfolio

https://github.com/sohailshams?tab=repositories

- HTML5 / CSS3 / Bootstrap/Git Version Control
  https://sohailshams.github.io/first-milestone-project/
- HTML5 / CSS3 / Bootstrap / JavaScript / JQuery / Google API/Git Version Control https://sohailshams.github.io/explore-copenhagen/
- Python / Flask / MongoDB / Materialize / Jinja template/Git Version Control http://mss-fitness-home.herokuapp.com/
- Python / Django / SQLite3 / Bootstrap / Stripe / AWS /Git Version Control

# **Skills:**

Creative	Proactive	Team Player
Fast-learner	Extrovert	Coordination
Innovative	Result Oriented	Communication
Analytic Thinker	Problem Solver	Service Minded
Organizer	Planner	Flexible

## **Experience:**

### **TR Trading**

Administrative Assistant / Taxi July 2019 till February 2020

• Effective communication with customers to create brand image

- Driving customers safely to their destinations
- Daily administrative tasks & paying out invoices

#### **GURU Copenhagen, Denmark**

Manager January 2011 till June 2017

- Assisting CEO to plan, develop & execute strategies
- Effective communication with team members to enhance the sales
- Oversee day to day operations of the restaurant
- Respond efficiently to the written and oral inquiries of the customers

### Apna Rozgar Toba Tek Singh, Pakistan

Volunteer October 2013 till Present

- Idea generation
- Fund Raising
- Helping people in setting up small business

# **Qualifications:**

#### **Code Institute Dublin, Ireland**

Diploma in Full Stack Software Development, 2020

Linnaeus University Kalmar, Sweden

Masters of Science in Marketing, June 2010

Government College University Faisalabad, Pakistan

Masters of Business Administration, December 2007

#### Government College of Science Faisalabad, Pakistan

Bachelors of Science, September 2004

### The Punjanb College Toba Tek Singh, Pakistan

Diploma in Computer Science May 2002

## **Language Skills:**

Urdu	Mother Tongue
English	Fluent
Danish	High intermediate level

# **Extracurricular activities and interest:**

- Spending time with family and friends
- Playing Cricket